Wrege, Charles D. Research Papers 6395
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series I: Western Electric and the Hawthorne Studies
  - pp. 100-105 Birth of the Talkies on Hawthorne Film, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Industrial Film Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Industrial Film Correspondence, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - alt.movies.silent, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Film Archives, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Hawthorne Film Search, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Madam, Will You Talk, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Moving Image Copyrights, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Silent Film Sources, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - E.B. Craft Data (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Dahelman on Bell Films (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Hawthorne Film "Muddy Waters" (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - The Search for "Hawthorne": Old Industrial Films Reveal New Insight Into Management History and Hawthorne Studies (Box 4, Folder 60)
- Series II: Hstory of Incandescent Lighiting
  - Gas Lighting (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Early Incandescent Lamp Patents before 1881 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    (From Edison Lab Records)
  - Early Incandescent lamp cover, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Early Electric Light Companies Based on Patents of Unknown Inventors, 1878-1889 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Dun & Brat Street and Early Lighting Companies (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Pages from a booklet on Electric Lighting History (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Wrege Lighting Data (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Lamp Reporter, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Unknown Manuscript of a History of Electric Lighting Industry to 1900, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    Purchased by NYG Bookstore
  - Early Electric Light Manuscript, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Purchased in NYC Bookstore, only remaining copy
  - Early Electric Light Manuscript (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - History of the Incandescent Lamp (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - History of Electric Light (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Introduction to "Lights that Failed" (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Brief Outline of Management Problems of Electric Industry 1840-1900, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Based on Early Electric Lamp Inventions
  - Francis W. Wilcox "The Practical Side of the Incandescent Lamp," N.E.L.A. 1901 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    pp. 132-178 on English's System of Lamp Renewals
  - Lamp Renewal Program in the Electric Industry (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Incandescent Lighting in US, 1847-1874 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Incandescent Light Correspondence, 1957-1964 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Isaac Adams Data (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Isaac Adams Lamp Data (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Drawings of Adams Lamps (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence of Elizabeth Adams and Isaac Adams, Jr. (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Sept. 14, 1854-August 2, 1865
  - Transactions and Letters from A. Caiffe to Dr. Isaac Adams, 1870-1874 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Copies of Original Letters from A. Caiffe to Dr. Isaac Adams, 1870-1874 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    in French
  - Articles on Adams (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Isaac Adams Correspondence, 1962-1977 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Bowdoin College News Service Article on Adams, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Isaac Adams and the Incandescent Lamp, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - RX For a Light: the Story of Dr. Isaac Adams, Jr., 1963 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - George Arons Data, 1902 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Cyrus Fogg Brackett Data (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - H. M. Collier and H. N. Baker Electric Lamp Patent No. 20, 255, 1858 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    May 18
  - Philip Diehl Data (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - John W. Draper Data, 1847 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Sherburne B. Eaton Data (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Thomas Edison Data (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Edison Lamp Data, 1873 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Edison Lamp Cases, 1881-1893 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Articles on Sunbury, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Edison System of Lamp Management (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Edison Correspondence on Free Lamp Renewals, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Edison's "Village" Central Station (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Forbes Article on Edison, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Edison Business Papers Project (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Edison Accounting Systems, 1870 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Association of Edison Illuminations Companies (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Association of Edison Illuminating Companies 8th Meeting, 1892 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Thomas Edison Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Charles Eisler Data (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Moses Farmer Data (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - James Billings Fuller Data (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Heinrich (Henry) Goebel Data (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - The Electric World Article on Goebel, 1893 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Manuscript for Goebel Chapter, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - John Guest Data (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Edward King Data (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - S. A. Kosloff Data (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Augustine Le Prince Data (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Abram Martin Data (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Hugo Munsterberg Data (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - William-Nickerson Data (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - D. J. Noyes (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Franklin L. Pope Data (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Edward Denmore Robbins Data (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - E.G.D. Rossell Data (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - William Sawyer Data (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - William Sawyer Edison Lab Data (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - William Sawyer Electro-Dynamic Light Data (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - William Sawyer Lamp Data (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Death of William Sawyer (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - William Sawyer Article Draft, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - William Sawyer Correspondence, 1962-1974 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Frank Spragne Data (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - John Starr Data (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - John Starr Lamp Data (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Sanders-Starr Lamp (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - The Mystery of Grave (Box 6, Folder 13)
    P-403
  - John Starr Correspondence, 1962-2001 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Article on John Starr, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Cincinnati Historical Society Article and Starr, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - E. Thompson Data (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Henry C. Townsend Data, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Westinghouse Data (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Zanus Wilbur Data (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - William Williams Data (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Henry Woodward and Matthew Swane Data (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Woodward-Evans Lamp Data (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Woodward Battery Data (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Walter Ebeling on the Woodward Lamp, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Partners in Light, 1876 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Woodward-Evans Correspondence, 1963-1975 (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Series III: Frederick W. Taylor
  - Taylor's Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Taylor Bethlehem Letters, 1900 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence Between F. W. Taylor and Gillespie, Josephine Goldmarie, A.R. Walleigh (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Sanford Thompson Correspondence, 1892-1896 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - A Conversation With P. A. Taylor, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - F. W. Taylor's Lectures on Management, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    4 June 1907
  - Taylor Interview, 1907 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    partial
  - F. W. Taylor's Notes for Talk on Management Given At Bethlehem Steel, 1899 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Taylor's Agreement with Sanford Thompson, 1895 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Taylor Wills (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Taylor's Supposed Three-Year Fight over Piece Rates (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Taylor Patents (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Maunsel White (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Taylor as foreman stories (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - F. W. Taylor and William Sellers (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Taylor and Simonds (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Story about discovery of heat treatment, 1908 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    10/31/1898
  - A. B. Wadleigh Shovel Study (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Charles McCollister "Turtle Creek Fights Back and the Westinghouse Strike of 1914" (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Taylor on Human Implements, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Dec. 30, 1897 - Engineer's license (stationary engineer) (Box 6, Folder 48)
    F. W. Taylor
  - Daniel Nelson on Taylor in his Book (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Charles Thomford - Pennsbury Manor on Edward Lewis and Edmund Lewis 1858 Map of Falls Township (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Taylor Accounting (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Caleb Taylor Data (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Data on Taylor's Family History (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Research Project on Companies Using Scientific Management, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - First Comprehensive Diagram of Taylor System Organization, 1905 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - List of Scientific Management Companies (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Clothcraft Shops, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Robert Kanigel Correspondence, 1992-1999 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Homer Jensen & Tacony Edge Tool Co. (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Taylor's "Flying Machine" (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Wrege's Correspondence on Taylor, 1957-2010 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Testimony of George Keim (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Report on Bethlehem reported by Taylor from Thompson, 1903 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - BATH - Supplement to FWT "Cutting Metals" from Art Bodleian (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Barth letters of December 21, 1925 on law of heavy laboring (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Correspondence on PBS Show on Taylor, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Shoveling - Gregory Galer, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - Dick Whiting Letters, 1978-1981 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Folder on Eric Breitbart's Clockwork, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - DATA Sheets for Taylor - Midvale Search, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Original MSS Paper to Taylor's paper "Shop Management", 1903 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    pp. 33-38, 41
  - Bill Payne letters on "Basley Search" Daniel Basley, Taylor's Accountant, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Data on Due Order and W. C. Whitney, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    July 19
  - Taylor Golf Photo (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Taylor in NY Times, 1911 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    June 7, 1911, p.8; April 28, 1911
  - Taylor Lecture June 7, 1907 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Original Pages
  - June Hartye Letters (Stevens Institute of Technology) on discovering Map of Management, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    March 3
  - New Orleans Paper (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - William M. Briggs, letter on Bethlehem Steel, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Taylor Book 3/24/65
  - Maine Historical Society (Box 7, Folder 13)
    and Barley
  - Map of Middletown, NJ, 1878 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - People Selecting Henry Morton as President of Stevens - and Possible Relation to Taylor (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Continental Mills, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence with Dr. Weldon P. Monson on Harry R. Towne, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    Feb. 5, 1961
  - Copies of F. B. Copley letters on Taylor Biography (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Baldwin Locomotive Works data (Box 7, Folder 19)
    use for Taylor in Philadelphia
  - Independent Research by Randy Wade (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Manuscript of F. W. Taylor & High Speed Steel for March 1995 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    Canal Museum Symposium
  - Phillip Wolle on Taylor, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Search for James Gillespie by Vito Ratti, 1966-1970 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    Taylor Book
  - A Collection of Original Frederick W. Taylor Documents, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Letters on the Souvenir Taylor Booklet, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    August-September
  - Spencer Klaw Article on Taylor, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - The Origins of Bookkeeping Under the Taylor System, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Flyers for Wrege's Taylor Book (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - F. W. Taylor and Industrial Espionage, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - J. C. Spender on Taylor, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Frederich W. Taylor: The "Father of Scientific Management", 1991 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Ms. Jackie Chivers, UDEN Associates, BBC Taylor Project, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Paper on High Speed Steel, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Canal Museum, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - High Speed Steel Paper (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Discovering Some of the Roots of Taylor's Shop Management (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Killing Off the Father, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - The Frederick Winslow Taylor Project, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 38)
- Series IV: Midvale Steel Company
  - Richmond and Potts Co. and Furnace for William Butcher Steel Works, 1869-1874 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Brooklyn Bridge News Items & Midvale Steel Works (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Shaws Well for Midvale, 1882-1883 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Seller's Data, 1882-1887 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    includes 1877 Map of Seller's Plant
  - "Steel for Guns & Armor Plates" The Railroad and Engineering, 1887 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    on Midvale
  - H. L. Gantt & George H. Chase Patent & Letter to Pete Petersen (Box 7, Folder 44)
    3/26/88
  - Howard C. Myers, Jr., 1944-1954 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - History of Midvale by Howard Myers, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Various Midvale letters from Howard C. Mysis papers obtained July, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Dawn der Blenker & Midvale Steel, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Patty Rice (and Falls of the Schuyhill Library), 1988 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Letter from Mrs. Hartye of Stevens on Midvale Photos of Mrs. Herme, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Marguerite Gibson PARK Corp, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Midvale records (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Figurer for Canal Paper - Midvale Steel (Box 7, Folder 53)
- Series V: Morris L. Cooke
  - "Industrial Management" MSS by M. L. Cooke, 1907 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    time study and task setting
  - FWT and MLC Manuscript of Industrial Management ch. 1, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Copy of Cooks and Taylors Manuscript for "Industrial Management", 1910 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Papers of Morris L. Cooke at Hyde Park, NY (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Cooke Correspondence, 1907-1912 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Cooke Correspondence, 1915 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Cooke Correspondence, 1920-1933 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Cooke Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Cooke's Production Flow Chart for "West's Ancient World" (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Benefits Accruing from Scientific Management, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Cooke's "That Ain't It" Taylor Story, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Data on Morris L. Cooke Death, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    NY Times March 10
  - Morris L. Cooke's Unpublished Book, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Analysis of Water Marks in Industrial Management, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Selection of M. L. Cooke for the Golden Book of Management, 1927 (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Cooke Creates A Classic, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Data on Cooke Residence in Philadelphia, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 70)
- Series VI: Frank B. Copley
  - Copley Version of Taylor MS (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Copley's Reporting of Midvale in Taylor's Biography (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Data on Frank B. Copley (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - Copley Search 1979 (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Copley & Taylor Biography (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Illustrations for Copley's Book on Taylor, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 76)
    1923 letters
  - Copley Taylor Biography, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Suggestions for Revision of the Life of F. W. Taylor (Box 7, Folder 78)
    by Frank Copley
  - Frank Copley Obituary & Book Announcement (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Copley Ms. Of Taylor Book - letter to E. W. Clark, 1920 (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - Harlow Person "Final Memorandum on Ms. Of Copley's Taylor", 1920 (Box 7, Folder 81)
    3 pages
  - Taylor Biography data (Box 7, Folder 82)
    Data on Frank B. Copley
  - Search for Author to Rewrite Taylor Biography (Box 7, Folder 83)
    includes Copley Death Certificate
- Series VII: Pig Iron Loading Studies
  - Pig Iron References (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - G & W Tables 1-11 (Walking experiments) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - From Principles of Scientific Management (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Data on the Ironmonger (use for Butcher Search) (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Pig Iron Report, 1899 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Gantt letters, 1899 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Bethlehem Steel vs. Niles-Bement-Pond, 1909 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Pig Iron in Industrial MST, 1907 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Gillespie & Wolle Original Time Study Forms, 1899 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Richard Stratton (Box 8, Folder 10)
    Cornwall Furnace
  - Pig Iron Greenwood Furnace (Box 8, Folder 11)
    Greenwood Furnace State Park, PA
  - Hopewell Furnace (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Robesonia Iron Company (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - New England Pig Iron (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - POD-Officers' Meeting, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Camden Factory (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - List of Pig Iron Workers (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Henry Noll Data (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Pig Iron Storage (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Carl Barth's Observation on the Loading of Half Pigs (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Frederick W. Taylor's Pig Iron Loading Observations, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Frederick W. Taylor's Pig Iron Experiments, 1899 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Non-pocketed Casts Data (Box 8, Folder 23)
    Sheets 1-29 Raw Data
  - Loading from Non-Pocketed Casts (Box 8, Folder 24)
    7,000 Ton Pile
  - PSM - Pig Iron, 1911 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Coonham to Taylor on Pig Iron Unloading, 1895 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Co. Lost. 86.41 Cost of Loading Pig Iron, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - 80,000 tons calculations (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Pig Iron Loading Diagrams (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - List of Mrs. Hearne's Midvale Photos (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Pig Iron Notes (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Letters and Data on Taylor's Pig Iron Study (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Craig Bartholomew (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Taylor's .22 Minutes to Load Pig Iron (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Calculations of Pig Iron Loading, 1899 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Calculations to Prone Inaccuracy of Taylor's .22 Minutes & 1156 Pigs (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Dimensions of full & 1/2 pigs, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Gondola Cars (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Weather (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - The Truth About Frederick W. Taylor's Stories About Pig Iron Loading: A Reply to Hough and White (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Copy of Manuscript on Taylor's "Pig Tale", 1971 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Taylor's "Pig Tale" Original Copy from Perroni, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Wrege and Hodgetts on Pig Iron AMF, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Pig Iron Story, 1907 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Frederick W. Taylor's "Pig Iron Loading Observations", 1998 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Using Stories to Create Change, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - A Microscopic Look at Frederick W Taylor: His Inaccuracies and Exaggerations, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    Draft
- Series VIII: Frank B. Gilbreth
  - Thomson letters to Frank Gilbreth in Pembrook, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - #20 Gilbreth Replications, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Figure 21 Carl Barth letter of September 21, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - "A Newly Discovered Gilbreth Manuscript" Academy of MST, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Charles Aldrich Search for John G. Aldrich of New England Co & The Gilbreth, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Analysis of Gilbreth Replication of Pig Iron Study, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Gilbreth Project Correspondence, 1979-2006 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Frank and Lillian Gilbreth Bring Order to Providence (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Irene Witte & The Quest (Box 8, Folder 56)
    Ferguson
- Series IX: Fatigue Studies
  - Industrial Fatigue Data: A Study of the Work of F.S. Lee and the Committee of Industrial Fatigue in 1918 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Fatigue Data (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Survey of Articles on Fatigue, 1920-1927 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Josephine Goldmark, Fatigue & Efficiency (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Data on Leonhard F. Fuld on Rest Periods, 1919 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Dr. Southard and Mary Jarrett on Medical Problems and Fatigue, 1919 (Box 8, Folder 62)
    p.2 on light & Industrial Fatigue
  - R. Spaeth "The Problem of Fatigue", 1919 (Box 8, Folder 63)
    #1 of Industrial Hygiene
  - F. S. Lee data - Robert Lozano Research into Dr. A. Baird Hastings and Dr. F. S. Lee, Fatigue Studies, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Bibliography from F. S. Lee, The Human Machine, Fatigue Studies & Hawthorne Studies, 1920 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Bibliography from F. S. Lee, The Human Machine, 1920 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Fasnam on Psychology in Europe and Gilbreth Fatigue Study, 1921 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Sources of Data on World War I Fatigue Studies - use for Hawthorne, 1917-1921 (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - letter 12/3/65 - from W. F. Mayles on Purdue Fatigue Thesis, 1921-1923 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Geupel, Goodin, Lavenstein, Shewmaker, & Sisloff Thesis at Purdue University on Rest Periods & Fatigue & Industrial Efficiency, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Two Contributions to the Study of Accident Causation, 1922 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - P. Sargent Florence, Economics of Fatigue and Unrest, 1923 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - Data on Industrial Fatigue Research Board (England) (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - IFRB Report #26 On the Extent and Effects of Variety in Repetitive Work, 1924 (Box 8, Folder 73)
  - IRFB Report #27 Results of Investigation in Certain Industries, 1924 (Box 8, Folder 74)
  - IFRB E. M. Bedale & H. M. Vernon, "The Effects of Posture & Rest in Muscular Work", 1924 (Box 8, Folder 75)
  - H. M. Vernon, "Can Laboratory Experiments on Output Throw Light on Problems of Industrial Fatigue", 1924-1925 (Box 8, Folder 76)
    British Journal of Psychology
  - J. D. Hackett - on Fatigue and Output, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Fatigue Articles, 1925-1926 (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - Henry C. Metcalf, "The Psychological Foundations of Management", 1927 (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Data from: Industrial Psychology, 1927-1928 (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Emily Ostome in Public Health, 1930 (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Survey of Fatigue articles referred to in Viteles, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Purdue Fatigue Study, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 83)
  - Information on Fatigue in Ryan: Work & Effort, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - Purdue Fatigue Test Correspondence, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - Search for British Fatigue Investigators of World War II, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Correspondence on Research Regarding Reynold Spaeth, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Baird Hastings on Fatigue Letters, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - Mayo on Fatigue in Human Problems of an Industrial Civilization, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - Correspondence & Data on Ernest Sonthard Plans by Mary Jarrett to Continue Mental Hygiene in Industry (Smith College) (Box 8, Folder 90)
  - Data on Harvard Fatigue Laboratory 1933, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Academy "Purdue Fatigue Tests" and Hawthorne Studies, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - Study to correct errors in Bibliography attached to Progress Report on Hawthorne Studies, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 93)
- Series X: Boxly: Frederick Taylor's Residence
  - Copy of Original Deed to "Boxly" Chestnut Hill (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Joseph S. Clark deed for "Boxly" estate site (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - "Sunford Thompson's drawings of forms for Taylor's Grass Experiments" at Boxly (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Boxly Article - Country Life in America, 1909 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Van DuZee Talk on "Boxly" - Taylor, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - "Boxly" in Penn Magazine of History & Biography, 1924 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Conrad Aiken & Taylor and Harold Van du Zee (died 5/7/17) "Boxly" (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Mrs. Hartage on Moving Boxwood at "Boxly" and Taylor Will, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - University of Pennsylvania Taylor Management Laboratory Research (Box 9, Folder 9)
    Boxly
  - Data on F. W. Taylor's Estate "Boxly" (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Draft for "The Story of Boxly", 2007 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - "Boxly Tour" (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Nov. 1999 on Boxly Story (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Address to the Boxly Book (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Johnathan Ziegert on Boxly, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Series XI: Rutgers University, the Academy of Management, and the History of Management
  - Tests, Rutgers University, Wrege, 1961-1962 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Records on Western Electric Training Program C. D. Wrege as Instructor, 1961-1962 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Original Ditta Sheets on History of Management for Rutgers (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Rutgers Data, 1962-1964 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Rutgers 1963 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Definitions for Management, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Western Electric Management Training, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Western Electric Management Training Program C.D. Wrege, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Data on Interaction Studies by Rutgers Students, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 24)